Preliminary Guide to the Helen Smith Bevington Papers, 1918-2001 RL.00108
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Helen Smith Bevington papers
1918-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bevington, Helen, 1906-2001
RL.00108
9.75 Linear Feet
3422 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Helen Smith Bevington Papers was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001.
Biographical Note
Helen Smith Bevington was a poet, professor in the English Department at Duke University, and resident of Durham (Durham Co.), N.C. Bevington's teaching specialty was modern poetry; she died in 2001.
Collection Overview
Family and personal papers, primarily Bevington's personal and professional correspondence (1931-2001), which includes letters from Ray Bradbury (1976-1993); typescripts of diary entries (1959-1989); 22 heavily annotated books of modern poetry, and research notes. There are also correspondence and professional records for Bevington's husband, Merle. Other items include one color and 9 black-and-white photographs, a scrapbook, passports, geneology information/records, awards, newspaper clippings, class records, and unpublished manuscripts.
Black-and-white photographs; Poetry, Modern; Clippings (information artifacts); Diaries; Color photographs; Poets, American -- 20th century; Authors, American -- 20th century; Scrapbooks; Bevington, Merle Mowbray,; Bevington, Helen, 1906-2001; Bevington, Helen, 1906-2001; Duke University; Duke University. Department of English; Bradbury, Ray,
- Accession 2001-0131
  - Diary, 1973 September 4-1989 December 31 (Box 1)
  - Diary, 1959 July-1973 September (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings, 1981-1993 (Box 3)
  - Calendar, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Annotated Books of Poetry, 17 volumes (Box 3)
  - Annotated Books of Poetry, 5 books (Box 4)
- Accession 2001-0143
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restrictions: Class records in Box 7 are restricted.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1937-1977, 2 books (Box 1)
  - Girl Graduate's Record Book, 1918-1924 (Box 1)
  - Booklet, Tom Mann: 80th Birthday Souvenir (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1943, one folder (Box 2)
  - Diaries, 1931-1934, 1990 January 1-1996 January 1, 4 folders (Box 2)
    Scope and Contents note
    Part of diary in box 1-2 of Accession 2001-0131
  - Miscellaneous Items, 3 folders (Box 2)
    Includes road maps, a hotel introduction booklet, postcards, etc.
  - Passport (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1978 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1978, cont. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1978, cont. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1978, cont. (Box 6)
  - Class Records, 1943-1975, 4 folders (Box 7)
    The class records in this box are restricted.
  - Notebook (Box 7)
  - Notes, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 7)
  - Programs for the "Reception in Honour of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth the Queen Mother" (Box 7)
  - Helen E. Smith master's thesis: " Thoreau as a Commentator on American Civilization" (Box 7)
  - Research notes on authors and their work (Box 8)
  - Unpublished book manuscript by Merle Bevington, one folder (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1941-2001, 9 folders (Box 9)
  - Family papers and certificates, one folder (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1996, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Publication notes and clippings, including material from Ray Bradbury, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Merle Bevington's personal documents, miscellaneous papers, and clippings, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Oversize materials (Box 11)
    - Scrapbook (Box 11)
    - Loose clippings (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Oversize (Oversize-folder 1)